Dongho Kang

Wasserwerkstrasse 12, Zurich 8006, Switzerland kangd@ethz.ch • +41 78 677 90 49 • https://donghok.me/

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research aims to create a legged robot that produces natural and animal-like motion. Thus, my research interests are broad ranging to legged locomotion control, computational model of character animation and design optimization for robotics applications.

EDUCATION

ETH Zürich, Zurich, Switzerland

Doctoral Student in Computer Science

Apr 2020 – Present

- Main advisor: Prof. Dr. Stelian Coros
- Second advisor: Prof. Dr. Marco Hutter
- M.Sc. ETH in Mechanical Engineering

Sep 2016 – Aug 2019

- Advisor: Prof. Dr. Marco Hutter
- · Graduated with distiction

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

■ B.Sc. in Mechanical Engineering and B.Sc. in Computer Science

Mar 2009 - Aug 2016

- Advisor: Prof. Dr. Dongjun Lee
- · Graduated with honor (Cum Laude)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Computational Robotics Lab, ETH Zürich

Scientific Assistant

Dec 2019 - Present

- Supervisors: Prof. Dr. Stelian Coros
- Aim to build bio-inspired quadrupedal robots that perform more natural and animal-like motion.

Robotic Systems Lab, ETH Zürich

Master's Student

Sep 2017 – Nov 2019

- Supervisors: David Höller, Dr. Jemin Hwangbo and Prof. Dr. Marco Hutter
- Conducted the research on learning-based collision avoidance for a legged robot ANYmal.
- Participated in the development of RaiSim: a physics engine for robotics and AI research.

Interactive & Networked Robotics Lab, Seoul National University

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Sep 2014 – Jan 2016

- Supervisors: Prof. Dr. Dongjun Lee
- Participated in the research on state estimation and control strategy for multi-robot cooperative systems

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS & ACTIVITIES

NVIDIA, Zurich, Switzerland

■ Deep Learning Intern

Jun 2018 - Dec 2018

• Projects: Super-Resolution and Anti-aliasing methods based on deep learning.

LeisureQ Inc., Seoul, South Korea

Web Developer Intern

Jan 2016 – Sep 2016

• Projects: Backend web application for E-commerce website Gajago: http://www.thegajago.com

CNP Technology Inc., Seoul, South Korea

Hardware and CAD Engineer

Jan 2016 - Sep 2016

PUBLICATIONS

CONFERENCES

- [1] Dongho Kang, Flavio De Vincenti, Naomi C. Adam, and Stelian Coros, "Animal Motions on Legged Robots Using Nonlinear Model Predictive Control," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, Oct 2022 (accepted).
- [2] Dongho Kang, Simon Zimmermann, and Stelian Coros, "Animal Gaits on Quadrupedal Robots using Motion Matching and Model-Based Control," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, Sep 2021.
- [3] Flavio De Vincenti, Dongho Kang, and Stelian Coros, "Control-Aware Design Optimization for Bio-Inspired Quadruped Robots," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, Sep 2021.

[4] Changu Kim, Hyunsoo Yang, <u>Dongho Kang</u> and Dongjun Lee, "2-D Cooperative Localization with Omni-Directional Mobile Robots," in *International Conference on Ubiquitous Robots and Ambient Intelligence*, Goyang, South Korea, Oct 2015.

WORKSHOP

[1] Dongho Kang, Flavio De Vincenti, and Stelian Coros, "Nonlinear Model Predictive Control for Quadrupedal Locomotion Using Second-Order Sensitivity Analysis," in *ICRA 2022: 6th Full-Day Workshop on Legged Robots*, May 2022.

THESIS

[1] Dongho Kang, "End-to-End Collision Avoidance from Depth Input with Memory-based Deep RL," Master's thesis, the Department of Mechanical and Process Engineering, ETH Zürich, Aug 2019.

Apr 2021

Dec 2019

Feb 2019

AWARDS &

SCHOLARSHIPS

INVITED TALK

Birkigt Scholarship, ETH Zürich
 Stipendiary scholarship for international master student.

Eminence Scholarship, Seoul National University
 Full-tuition scholarship for one academic semester for outstanding academic performance.

Merit-based Scholarship, Seoul National University
 Half-tuition scholarship for one academic semester for outstanding academic performance.

Development Fund Scholarship, Seoul National University
 Full-tuition scholarship for one academic year for outstanding academic performance.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

ETH Zürich, Zurich, Switzerland

Teaching Assistant, Linear Algebra (Autumn)
 Teaching Assistant, Computational Models of Motion (Spring)
 Teaching Assistant, Visual Computing (Autumn)
 2021 – 2022
 Teaching Assistant, Visual Computing (Autumn)

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

• Robot Intelligence Lab, Korea University, Seoul, South Korea

• Max Planck ETH Center for Learning Systems Symposium, Tübingen, Germany

NAVER LABS Corp., Seoul, South Korea

Mentor, SNU Samsung Convergence Software Course Program
 Teaching Assistant, MAE 446.204A: Dynamics
 Teaching Assistant, PA 034.013: Basic Physics 2
 Sep 2011 – Dec 2011

LANGUAGES

- Korean: Native language.
- English: Fluent.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming and Software

C/C++, C#, Python, Matlab/Octave, Unix/Linux, Tensorflow, Pytorch, ROS, Open Dynamics Engine, Unity

Experience with Robots

UnitreeRobotics Aliengo, A1, Go1, ANYbotics ANYmal

REFERENCES

■ Prof. Dr. Stelian Coros

Associate Professor in the Department of Computer Science ETH Zürich

Stampfenbachstrasse 48 (Sumatrastrasse 11), 8092, Zurich, Switzerland scoros@inf.ethz.ch • +41 44 632 02 15

■ Prof. Dr. Marco Hutter

Associate Professor in the Department of Mechanical and Process Engineering ETH Zürich Leonhardstrasse 21, 8092 Zurich, Switzerland

mahutter@ethz.ch • +41 44 632 74 17

■ Prof. Dr. Jemin Hwangbo

Assistant Professor in the Department of Mechanical Engineering Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology jhwangbo@kaist.ac.kr

■ Prof. Dr. Dongjun Lee

Professor in the Department of Mechanical Engineering Seoul National University 1 Gwanak-Ro, Gwanak-Gu, Seoul, 08826, South Korea djlee@snu.ac.kr • +82 2 880 1724